# Edgar Filipe da Silva Domingues

### Software Engineer

I'm a software engineer with **over 8 years** of experience and a passion for solving real world problems. I accept a challenge as both an opportunity to learn something new and to apply what I know. I put my best in everything I do, having "kaizen" in my mind, I continuously improve my work and the work of my team. I follow agile and lean software development practices to increase business value and client satisfaction. I have experience working with teams of different cultures and languages, both onsite and remote, and developing software for different areas, including robotics, telecommunications, e-commerce, fintech and banking. On my free time I'm either programming side projects or outside enjoying nature by doing orienteering, running or biking. I'm a volunteer in organizing, supervising and course setting of orienteering events.

## **Experience**

# **Isobar Switzerland**, Leiria – *Software Engineer / Senior Consultant* 2016-12 – present

- Developed Client Onboarding solutions for banks using Java Spring BPM engines.
- Full stack developer in B2B e-shop using jQuery and SAP Hybris.
- Implemented plugins for Atlassian's Jira using Java and Angular.
- Worked remotely with distributed teams around the world.
- Tech lead of a team of 3 developers.
- Did technical interviews and helped in the recruitment and hiring processes.

#### La Redoute, Leiria – Software Engineer

2014-09 - 2016-12

- Development of the back-end to handle the life cycle of orders from request until shipping.
- Created Java Spring Batch applications to process large quantities of data in an efficient way.
- Migrated COBOL programs to Java Spring and integrated them with legacy systems.
- Developed Stored Procedures to update the database efficiently and assuring data integrity.
- Launch to production of an important transformation project by managing the team, allocating work and reporting to upper management.

## Portugal Telecom Inovação, Aveiro - Software Engineer

2011-09 - 2014-09

- Developed software for research projects and for products, in the areas of context-awareness, social networks, connection management, VoIP, etc.
- Created application for Windows, Android and iPhone (in Java, C/C++, C# and Objective-C).
- Worked in the European Union research project SOCIETIES and in the product MyConnect/MEO Connect.
- Implemented the OpenSocial specification using Java J2EE and integrated with Social Networks like Facebook, Twiter and Google+.
- Worked in the development of SIP softphones for Android and iOS.
- Developed Windows applications that interact with AT modems and SIM cards.

## **Education**

## **University of Aveiro** – M.Sc. in Computers and Telematics Engineering 2009-2011

Dissertation: "Development of Behaviors for Humanoid Robot"

Publications: "Humanoid Behaviors: from Simulation to a Real Robot", EPIA 2011, Springer

**University of Aveiro** – Degree in Computers and Telematics Engineering 2006 - 2009

## **Certifications and Training**

- Certified Professional Developer Appway (2018-04)
- Certified Scrum Master (CSM) Scrum Alliance (2017-05)
- French Classes Linécole (2016-07)
- Test-Driven Development Practices in Java pluralsight.com (2016-05)
- Training in Trail Orienteering Course Setting and Planning Portuguese Orienteering Federation (2015-12)
- Training in Technology Project Management PT Inovação (2013-10)
- Advanced training in SIP PT Inovação (2013-06)
- Training "jRuby on Rails" PT Inovação (2012-07)

### **Personal Info**

#### E-mail

edgar.domingues@gmail.com

#### **Phone**

+351 91 415 56 85

#### **Address**

Rua Comendador Santos Barosa, 1, 2430-268 Marinha Grande, Portugal

#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/edgar-domingues

#### Web

edgardomingues.com

### **Technical Skills**

Java, Spring, SQL, HTML, CSS, Less, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Git, BPM, Appway, COBOL, DB2, AS400, SOAP, REST, Maven, JUnit, Mockito, Cerberus, C/C++, C#, Android SDK and NDK, iOS, Objective-C, Kotlin, Python, Flutter, Dart, Solidity, Gherkin, Cucumber, Scrum, TDD, BDD

#### **Awards**

- 2<sup>nd</sup> place WTOC 2016
- Highest grade finalist in the engineering courses of 2011.
- Merit scholarship in 2007/2008 and 2010/2011.
- Honor student on high school.
- 3º place in the Microsoft Webmaster 2006.

#### **Interests**

- Orienteering
- Traveling
- Photography
- BlockchainAutomation